<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on n0rdy personal blog</title>
    <link>https://n0rdy.foo/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on n0rdy personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://n0rdy.foo/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Ghostty - a new and quite promising terminal emulator</title>
      <link>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20250118/til-ghostty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20250118/til-ghostty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following my blog, you might have noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m usually leaning towards longreads as the style of my posts. And while I think such posts are great in general, it takes forever to prepare, write and edit them before publishing, which ends up in the very infrequent and inconsistent blogging ratio on my end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2022/Nov/6/what-to-blog-about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;“What to blog about”&lt;/a&gt; article by Simon Willison which, alongside other things, had a great insight about the “Today I Learned” type of short posts to share small bits of recently acquired knowledge with the audience. So, this is my attempt to incorporate that approach alongside the longreads that I will keep writing (I have a few topics planned, so stay tuned and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mail.n0rdy.foo/subscription/form&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;subscribe to my newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to receive an email once I publish a new post). Let&amp;rsquo;s gooooooo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying OTPs: the logic behind the offline generation of tokens</title>
      <link>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20241210/otp-offline-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20241210/otp-offline-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! Another evening, on my way back home, I decided to check the mailbox. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean my email inbox, but the old-school actual box where the postman puts the physical letters. And to my great surprise, I found an envelope there with something inside! While opening it, I spent a few moments hoping that it&amp;rsquo;s the decades delayed letter from Hogwarts. But then I had to get back down to Earth, once I noticed that it&amp;rsquo;s a boring &amp;ldquo;grown-up&amp;rdquo; letter from the bank. I skimmed through the text and realized that my &amp;ldquo;digital-only&amp;rdquo; bank for cool kids had been acquired by the biggest player on the local market. And as a token of the new beginning, they added this to the envelope:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI tools for software engineers: 5 things to be careful about/aware of</title>
      <link>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20231226/ai-tools-for-software-engineers-limits-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 15:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://n0rdy.foo/posts/20231226/ai-tools-for-software-engineers-limits-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! 2023 is about to end soon, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to sit and reflect on it. If we think about the tech industry, in general, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to define which topic was the hottest this year - AI. And the chances are that in 2024, this area will grow even bigger alongside the growing investments and the new astonishing scientific discoveries in this field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous &amp;ldquo;big things&amp;rdquo; in tech, like blockchain, crypto, NFT, Web3, etc., AI is way more accessible and covers more use cases than the rest:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
